<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Ronald&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Ronald&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ronald Bosma - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanitizing Response Headers in API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/24/sanitizing-response-headers-in-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/24/sanitizing-response-headers-in-api-management/</guid>
      <description>By default, Azure API Management returns all headers from the backend to the client, which may include sensitive information. This post demonstrates three approaches to sanitizing response headers: explicit removal, allowlist-based filtering and blocklist-based filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs from Azure DevOps Using Federated Credentials</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/10/call-oauth-protected-apis-from-azure-devops-using-federated-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/10/call-oauth-protected-apis-from-azure-devops-using-federated-credentials/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to execute automated integration tests against OAuth-protected APIs from Azure DevOps pipelines using federated credentials. This enables secure API testing without managing secrets in your CI/CD pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs from GitHub Actions Using Federated Credentials</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/03/call-oauth-protected-apis-from-github-actions-using-federated-credentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/11/03/call-oauth-protected-apis-from-github-actions-using-federated-credentials/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to execute automated integration tests against OAuth-protected APIs from GitHub Actions workflows using federated credentials. This enables secure API testing without managing secrets in your CI/CD pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected Backends from API Management using Send-Request Policy with Client Certificate</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/20/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-send-request-policy-with-client-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/20/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-send-request-policy-with-client-certificate/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to implement certificate-based OAuth authentication in API Management using JWT assertions and the send-request policy. This approach provides stronger security than client secrets by proving possession of a private key without transmitting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected Backends from API Management using Send-Request Policy with Client Secret</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/13/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-send-request-policy-with-client-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/13/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-send-request-policy-with-client-secret/</guid>
      <description>When API Management&amp;rsquo;s credential manager isn&amp;rsquo;t suitable for your OAuth scenarios, you can implement token handling directly using policies. In this post, I show how to call OAuth-protected backends using the send-request policy with Client Credentials Flow and a client secret stored in Key Vault.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected Backends from API Management using Credential Manager</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/06/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-credential-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/06/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-credential-manager/</guid>
      <description>Azure API Management&amp;rsquo;s credential manager provides a simple, managed way to handle OAuth flows with automatic token acquisition and caching. In this post, I show how to configure it using Bicep and integrate it into your APIs. I also highlight key considerations to help you decide when credential manager is the right choice versus custom token handling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/29/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/29/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-api-management/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use API Management to call OAuth-protected APIs with managed identity. This enables secure API-to-API communication and privilege delegation patterns without managing secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from Logic Apps</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/24/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-logic-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/24/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-logic-apps/</guid>
      <description>Azure Logic Apps Standard makes it easy to call OAuth-protected APIs using managed identity. This post demonstrates how to use the HTTP action&amp;rsquo;s built-in authentication and token caching for secure, reliable calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from .NET</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/20/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/20/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-.net/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to call OAuth-protected APIs from .NET applications using Azure managed identity. This post shows how to implement secure API calls from Azure Functions without managing secrets, using the Azure Identity library and custom HTTP message handlers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect APIs in Azure API Management with OAuth</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/16/protect-apis-in-azure-api-management-with-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/16/protect-apis-in-azure-api-management-with-oauth/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to secure APIs in Azure API Management with OAuth 2.0 and Microsoft Entra ID using a fully automated, infrastructure-as-code approach. This post walks through deploying everything with Bicep, including app registrations via the Microsoft Graph Bicep extension, so you can avoid manual portal setup and ensure repeatable deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing backend connections with mTLS in API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/05/24/securing-backend-connections-with-mtls-in-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/05/24/securing-backend-connections-with-mtls-in-api-management/</guid>
      <description>In this third post on working with client certificates in Azure API Management, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on securing backend connections with mTLS. We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy two API Management instances. The first will serve as the backend and require a client certificate for authentication. The second will act as the client. We will call the client using TLS, and it will, in turn, connect to the backend using mTLS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validate client certificates in API Management when it&#39;s behind an Application Gateway</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/19/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management-when-its-behind-an-application-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/19/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management-when-its-behind-an-application-gateway/</guid>
      <description>In this second post, we expand on the solution from the previous post. We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy API Management inside a virtual network, positioning it behind an application gateway. We&amp;rsquo;ll configure the application gateway with an mTLS listener to validate client certificates and forward them to API Management for further processing. This approach can also be used with other types of backends, such as an ASP.NET Web API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validate client certificates in API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/02/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/02/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is the start of a series on how to work with client certificates in Azure API Management to setup a mutual TLS (mTLS) connection. While Azure&amp;rsquo;s official documentation provides excellent guidance on setting up client certificates via the Azure Portal, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into utilizing Bicep and the Azure CLI, to automate the process. In this first post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of how to validate client certificates in API Management.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
