<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OAuth on Ronald&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/oauth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OAuth on Ronald&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ronald Bosma - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/oauth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected Backends from API Management using Credential Manager</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/06/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-credential-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/10/06/call-oauth-protected-backends-from-api-management-using-credential-manager/</guid>
      <description>Azure API Management’s credential manager provides a simple, managed way to handle OAuth flows with automatic token acquisition and caching. In this post, I show how to configure it using Bicep and integrate it into your APIs. I also highlight key considerations to help you decide when credential manager is the right choice versus custom token handling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/29/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/29/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-api-management/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use API Management to call OAuth-protected APIs with managed identity. This enables secure API-to-API communication and privilege delegation patterns without managing secrets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from Logic Apps</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/24/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-logic-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/24/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-logic-apps/</guid>
      <description>Azure Logic Apps Standard makes it easy to call OAuth-protected APIs using managed identity. This post demonstrates how to use the HTTP action’s built-in authentication and token caching for secure, reliable calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call OAuth-Protected APIs with Managed Identity from .NET</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/20/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/20/call-oauth-protected-apis-with-managed-identity-from-.net/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to call OAuth-protected APIs from .NET applications using Azure managed identity. This post shows how to implement secure API calls from Azure Functions without managing secrets, using the Azure Identity library and custom HTTP message handlers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect APIs in Azure API Management with OAuth</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/16/protect-apis-in-azure-api-management-with-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2025/09/16/protect-apis-in-azure-api-management-with-oauth/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to secure APIs in Azure API Management with OAuth 2.0 and Microsoft Entra ID using a fully automated, infrastructure-as-code approach. This post walks through deploying everything with Bicep, including app registrations via the Microsoft Graph Bicep extension, so you can avoid manual portal setup and ensure repeatable deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
