<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Ronald&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Ronald&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Ronald Bosma - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 19:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ronaldbosma.github.io/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Validate client certificates in API Management when it&#39;s behind an Application Gateway</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/19/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management-when-its-behind-an-application-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/19/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management-when-its-behind-an-application-gateway/</guid>
      <description>In this second post, we expand on the solution from the previous post. We&amp;rsquo;ll deploy API Management inside a virtual network, positioning it behind an application gateway. We&amp;rsquo;ll configure the application gateway with an mTLS listener to validate client certificates and forward them to API Management for further processing. This approach can also be used with other types of backends, such as an ASP.NET Web API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validate client certificates in API Management</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/02/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2024/02/02/validate-client-certificates-in-api-management/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is the start of a series on how to work with client certificates in Azure API Management to setup a mutual TLS (mTLS) connection. While Azure&amp;rsquo;s official documentation provides excellent guidance on setting up client certificates via the Azure Portal, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into utilizing Bicep and the Azure CLI, to automate the process. In this first post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of how to validate client certificates in API Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Azure Workbook and App Insights Function</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2023/03/10/deploy-azure-workbook-and-app-insights-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2023/03/10/deploy-azure-workbook-and-app-insights-function/</guid>
      <description>In this post I explain how to deploy an Azure workbook using Bicep and set environment specific variables. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show how to deploy a shared kusto function in Application Insights with the Azure CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Workbook Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/azure-workbook-tips-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2023/02/28/azure-workbook-tips-tricks/</guid>
      <description>If you use Azure, you most likely use Application Insights for logging. You can use a dashboard to visualize your logging and gain better insights, but dashboards come with some limitations. For more flexibility Azure has worbooks. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll share some tips &amp;amp; tricks that I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the years. As a sample, we&amp;rsquo;ll create a workbook that shows information about requests sent to an API Management instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provision an Azure VM in an Azure Pipelines Environment</title>
      <link>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2021/03/16/provision-an-azure-vm-in-an-azure-pipelines-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ronaldbosma.github.io/blog/2021/03/16/provision-an-azure-vm-in-an-azure-pipelines-environment/</guid>
      <description>In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve created a custom Azure Pipelines task to install .NET Core on a Windows server. To test this task, I had to manually setup an environment with virtual machines. I wanted to automate this process, so I created a YAML pipeline in Azure DevOps that automatically provisions an Azure virtual machine and registers the virtual machine in an Azure Pipelines environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
